(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
平成初期アニソン祭り
不知火フレア 4th anniversary
Early Heisei Anime Song Festival
Shiranui Flare 4th Anniversary
夢の国を探す君の名を
Searching for your name, seeking the land of dreams
WILL
作詞：米倉千尋・徳永英三
作曲：徳永英三
WILL
Lyrics: Chihiro Yonekura, Eizo Tokunaga
Composition: Eizo Tokunaga
誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone carves it into their hearts
悲しみ乗り越えた微笑みに
In the smile that overcame sadness
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
終わりがなくて 見つけられなくって
Endless and unable to find
迷ったりしたけれど
I wandered, but...
傷ついたこと 失ったもの
The things that hurt, the things I lost
いつかは輝きに変えて
I'll turn them into radiance someday
後悔に決して負けない翼が
Wings that will never yield to regret
きっとあるから
I'm sure they are there
君とならどこでも
With you, anywhere...
行ける気がする
I feel like I can go
夢の国を探す君の名を
Searching for your name, seeking the land of dreams
誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone carves it into their hearts
悲しみ乗り越えた微笑みに
In the smile that overcame sadness
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
みなさーん、こんぬいー！
Hello everyone, Konnui!
不知火フレアです！
I'm Shiranui Flare!
今日は私の4周年記念LIVE「平成初期アニソン祭り」へようこそ！
Welcome to my 4th anniversary live, "Early Heisei Anime Song Festival", today!
1曲目は「仙界伝 封神演義」のオープニングテーマ「WILL」でした！
The first song was "WILL", the opening theme of "Senkaiden Houshin Engi"!
今日はね、みんなが知ってる懐かしい曲をたくさん用意してきたから、
Today, I've prepared many nostalgic songs that everyone knows,
一人ぼっちじゃ 生きて行けないって
You told me that I can't live all alone
あの時教えてくれた
You taught me that back then
近くにあっても 気付かずにいた
Even when they were close by, I didn't notice
本当に大切なこと
The things that are truly important
この宇宙の果てに 何が待っていても
No matter what awaits at the edge of this universe
きっと大丈夫
I'm sure it'll be okay
その瞳に映る未来 感じてるから
Because I feel the future reflected in those eyes
夢の国を探す 君の名を
Your name, as you search for a dreamland
誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone carves it into their hearts
偶然じゃない 運命の中で
In a fate that is no coincidence
君の奇跡を信じてる
I believe in your miracle
夢の楽園を 探しながら
While searching for a dream paradise
走る君を見つめていたい
I want to keep watching you run
誇り高く 汚れを知らない
So proud and pure
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
夢の国を探す 君の名を
Your name, as you search for a dreamland
誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone carves it into their hearts
悲しみ乗り越えた 微笑みに
In that smile that overcame sadness
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
夢の楽園を 探しながら
While searching for a dream paradise
走る君を見つめていたい
I want to keep watching you run
誇り高く 汚れを知らない
So proud and pure
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
はい、ということで！
All right, then!
こんぬいー！ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
Kon-nui! I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
今日は遅れてきた私の4周年記念ライブに来てくれて、どうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my late 4th anniversary live today!
最初の一曲目を聞いていただきましたが...
You just heard the first song...
今回のテーマはなんと！平成初期アニソン祭り！
The theme this time is... Early Heisei Era Anisong Festival!
思わず「こういうのがいいんだよ」って言いたくなっちゃうかも？
You might find yourself saying, "This is exactly what I needed."
みんなの好きだったあんな曲やこんな曲を歌えたら嬉しいなって思ってます。
I hope I can sing all those songs you guys loved.
ゲストもたくさんいるから、楽しみにしててね！
There are lots of guests too, so look forward to it!
みんなで一緒に楽しんでくれると嬉しいので、ハッシュタグもぜひ活用してください！
I'd be happy if we could all enjoy this together, so please use the hashtag!
ハッシュタグはこちら、
The hashtag is this:
「#不知火フレア4周年記念LIVE」で、画像と一緒にたくさんツイートしてください！
"#ShiranuiFlare4thAnniversaryLIVE". Please tweet a lot with images!
最後にお知らせもあるから、最後までたくさん楽しんでってください！
There's an announcement at the end, so please enjoy yourself until the very end!
おっ？早速だけど、どこかでゲストの声がする...
Oh? Right away, I can hear a guest's voice somewhere...
どこだろう？
I wonder where?
輝きは君の中に
Brightness is inside of you
楽しいことでも 毎日続いたら
Even fun things, if they continue every day
それと気付かずに 退屈と
I might not notice it and call it boredom
変わらないで
Without changing
幸せ悲しみ 代わる代わるの波
Waves of happiness and sadness, one after another
心の不思議が 分かりかけてくる
I'm starting to understand the mystery of the heart
人を愛したら 不安も知るものだけど
When you love someone, you also get to know anxiety, but
寂しい心に 深く
Deep in a lonely heart
輝きは君の中に
The Sparkle Is Within You
小さく
A small sting...
しみるよ
...deep inside.
ジグザグ迷い続けてる
Continuing to wander in a zigzag...
近道なんてないのかな
Is there no shortcut, I wonder?
だけど 楽しいだけならば
But if it's only about having fun,
きっと 幸せ 見失う
I'm sure I'll lose sight of happiness.
まっすぐ自分も言葉
Directly, both myself and my words,
君に届かないときは
When they don't reach you,
ふいに無口になるけれど
I suddenly become silent, but...
いつかどこかで 感じあえる
Someday, somewhere, we can feel each other's presence.
悲しみを避けて
Avoiding sadness
笑うのは簡単
Is easy to do
諦め上手な大人に
I don't want to become
なりたくない
An adult who's good at giving up
自分ひとりだけ
When I feel like I'm the only one
空回りしてると
Spinning my wheels
誰もが器用に
It feels like everyone else
生きてる気がする
Is living so skillfully
人は傷つけて
People hurt others
自分を守るよ
To protect themselves
朝は虚しさを残して
The morning leaves a sense of emptiness,
やがて 自分も傷つく
And eventually, I end up hurting too.
ジグザグ迷い続けても
Even if we keep wandering in a zigzag,
振り返れば煌めいてる
When we look back, it's sparkling.
つらい別れのあと独り
Even that time after a painful parting when I sat alone,
膝を抱えてたことも
Holding my knees.
まっすぐ自分の気持ち
On the day my direct feelings
君に届いたその日は
Reach you,
きっと涙があふれるね
I'm sure tears will overflow.
愛を信じた答えだから
Because that's the answer to believing in love.
I can't stop my love for you
作詞：愛内里菜 作曲：川島だりあ
Lyrics: Aiuchi Rina, Composition: Kawashima Daria
I can't stop my love for you
二人の重なる未来に
In our overlapping future,
君との居場所があるように
I hope there's a place for me with you.
Oh baby, I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね
Please become my everything.
繋いだ手信じて
Believing in our joined hands,
歩いて行くと誓うよ
I swear to keep walking.
二人の目の前 謎めく広がり
Before the two of us, a mysterious expanse...
未完成な地図
An incomplete map,
でもとても とても心動いた
But it moved my heart so, so much.
どんな言葉並べてみても
No matter what words I line up,
語りきれない想い
These feelings can't be fully told.
この愛が ささやくよ
This love whispers,
愛しいと
"You are dear to me."
I can't stop my love for you ❤️
...の意味を
...the meaning of...
I can't stop my love for you
二人歩むスピードは
The speed at which we two walk...
きっと同じはずじゃないからね
...surely won't be the same.
もしも君の隣に　この手が離れた時は
If, when I'm by your side, this hand should let go...
見失わないように　きっと　迎えに来てね
...so you don't lose sight of me, please come for me.
大嫌いなんて　嘘でも言わないけど
I wouldn't say I hate you, even as a lie.
大好きだって　嘘なんかじゃ意味ないからね
Because saying I love you means nothing if it's a lie.
会えない時さえ君は　何も考える余裕もないくらい
Even when we can't meet, I don't have time to think of anything else...
この心　独り占めにするんだから
...because you've taken over my heart.
I can't stop my love for you
二つの愛が離れて
So our two loves don't...
しまわないように一つに抱いてて
...drift apart, hold them as one.
それでも不安な夜は　訪れるものだからね
Even so, nights of anxiety will still come.
そんな時はぎゅっと　大袈裟に抱きしめていて
At those times, hold me tight, even if it's an exaggeration.
かけがえのない今を　君が沢山ここにくれた
You've given me so much of this irreplaceable "now".
だけど何よりも一番　かけがえのないものは
But the thing that's more irreplaceable than anything else...
君なんだ
...is you.
I can't stop my love for you
二人が辿る未来に
In the future we two follow...
君との居場所があるように
...I hope there's a place for me by your side.
Oh baby I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね
Be my everything.
繋いだ手信じて　歩いてゆくと誓うよ
Believing in our joined hands, I vow to walk on.
輪舞-revolution / 作詞：奥井雅美 作曲：矢吹俊郎
Rondo-revolution / Lyrics: Masami Okui, Composition: Toshiro Yabuki
潔く カッコよく 生きてゆこう
Let's live purely and coolly.
たとえ二人離ればなれになっても
Even if we two are pulled apart...
Take my revolution
光さす庭で手を取り合い
Joining hands in the sunlit garden...
誓い合ったなぐさめ合った
...we made vows and comforted each other.
もう恋は二度としないよって
Saying we'd never fall in love again.
そんな強い結束は形を変え
That strong bond has changed its form...
今じゃこんなに逞しい私達の
...to our current, resilient...
ライフスタイル エブリディ エブリタイム
...lifestyle, every day, every time.
頬寄せ合って写る写真の笑顔に
In the smiles of the photos taken with cheeks together...
少しの寂しさ詰め込んで
...I packed a little bit of loneliness.
潔く カッコよく 明日からは
Purely and coolly, from tomorrow...
誰もが振り向く女になる
...I'll become a woman everyone turns to look at.
たとえ二人離ればなれになっても
Even if we two are pulled apart...
心はずっと一緒に
...our hearts will always be together.
...いられないね
...can't stay as you are.
若い子みんなそうだと 思われるのは
I don't like it when people think
all young kids are like that.
不本意で どうしようもないじゃない
It's so frustrating and there's nothing I can do.
でもね
But you know...
私たち友達のこと 何より大切にしてる
We treasure our friends more than anything else.
きっと大人よりも
Even more than adults, I'm sure.
夢を見て 涙して 傷ついても
Even if we dream, cry, and get hurt...
現実は がむしゃらに来るし
Reality comes at us relentlessly.
自分の居場所 存在価値は 失くせない
We can't lose our place or the value of our existence.
自分を守るために
In order to protect ourselves.
あのアドバルーン 戻れない
That ad-balloon won't return...
それぞれの 道を選ぶ時が来る前に
...before the time comes for us to choose our own paths.
こんなにも こんなにも 大切な
These precious memories...
思い出 解き放つよ
...so many of them, I will set them free.
Take my revolution 生きて行こう
Take my revolution, let's live on.
現実は がむしゃらに来るし
Reality comes at us relentlessly.
自分の居場所 存在価値を 見つけたい
I want to find my place and the value of my existence.
今日までの自分を
Everything about myself up until today...
潔く 脱ぎ捨てる 裸になる
...I'll resolutely cast off and lay myself bare.
自由を舞う 薔薇のように
Like a rose dancing in freedom.
たとえ二人 離ればなれになっても
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
私は世界を変える
I will change the world.
Go-Round
作詞：浜口祐夢 作曲：Face 2 FAKE
Lyrics: Hamaguchi Megumi, Music: Face 2 FAKE
奇跡の風が 胸吹き抜ける
A miraculous wind blows through my chest.
ちょっぴり強くなれる気がして
I feel like I can become a little stronger.
純情なMy感情が
My innocent emotions...
騒ぎ出す
...begin to stir.
知らず知らずに 鍵をかけていた
Without even realizing it, I had locked them away.
Love Heart たちよ 今こそ
Oh, Love Hearts, now is the time.
有象無象の剣を
Those miscellaneous swords...
振り解き放て
...shake them off and set them free.
きらめきをバックに詰め込んで
Packing the sparkle into my bag.
君が笑う 楽園へ行こう
Let's go to the paradise where you smile.
不思議なパワー 二人で
This mysterious power, with the two of us...
呼び覚ませ
...let's awaken it.
回れMerry-go-round めくるめくFuture
Spin, Merry-go-round, a dazzling future.
負けないくらい 信じて
Believe enough not to lose.
響け夢にGo-round 抱きしめ太陽
Echo to the dreams, Go-round, embrace the sun.
きっと虹になる 今まで
It will surely become a rainbow, even now.
回れMerry-go-round 大事なMessage
Spin, Merry-go-round, an important message.
忘れないで 今すぐ
Don't forget it, right now.
君の胸にGo-round 今伝えたいんだ
Into your heart, Go-round, I want to tell you now...
愛は無敵だと
...that love is invincible.
ガラスの扉 激しく叩いて
Banging hard on the glass door.
見つめたい自分を 映して
Reflecting the self I want to look at.
迷わずに 次のステージへ
Without hesitation, to the next stage...
舞い上がれ
...soar high!
不安なAdventure 信じて
Believe in the uneasy adventure.
息を止めて 口づけをしたら
If we hold our breath and share a kiss...
未来のEnergy あふれ出して
The energy of the future will overflow...
くるよ
...and come to us!
まわれ Merry-go-round
Go round, Merry-go-round
輝ける Future
The shining future
切ないくらい感じて
Feel it so much it hurts
なぜか二人 Go-round
Somehow the two of us go round
出会えたことを
The fact that we met
ずっと大切にしたい
I want to treasure it forever
まわれ Merry-go-round
Go round, Merry-go-round
楽しい Story
The fun story
感じたまま競おう
Let's compete just as we feel
君のために Go-round
Go round for you
指切りしよう
Let's make a pinky promise
愛を離さない
Don't let go of love
まわれ Merry-go-round
Go round, Merry-go-round
めくるめく Future
The dazzling future
負けないくらい信じて
Believe so much you won't lose
強く夢に Go-round
Go round strongly for the dream
抱きしめたいよ
I want to hold you tight
虹になる日まで
Until the day it becomes a rainbow
まわれ Merry-go-round
Go round, Merry-go-round
大事な Message
The important message
忘れないで今すぐ
Don't forget it, right now
君の胸に Go-round
Go round in your heart
今伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you now
愛は無敵だと
That love is invincible
まわれ Merry-go-round
Go round, Merry-go-round
楽しい Story
The fun story
感じたまま競おう
Let's compete just as we feel
君のために Go-round
Go round for you
指切りしよう
Let's make a pinky promise
愛を離さない
Don't let go of love
夢を守るよ
I'll protect the dream
Successful Mission
君を守るためこの地に
In this land to protect you
君と出会うため生まれた
I was born to meet you
目覚めた瞬間
The moment I woke up
廻りはじめるプリズム
The prism begins to rotate
君を愛するために今
Now, to love you
君を抱くため生まれた
I was born to embrace you
嘘も真実も
Both lies and truth
全て自分の中にある
Everything is inside myself
心置き去りにしている
My heart has been left behind
日々に負けない
I won't lose to the passing days
やさしさ
Kindness
愛しさ
Preciousness
もう一度 取りもどそう
Let's reclaim them once again
操り人形な毎日の中で
In days like being a puppet
ゼロと無限のはざまを迷っている
Wandering between zero and infinity
絡まった糸を
The tangled threads
断ち切る力は
The power to cut through them
君の心の中にまだ眠っている
Still lies dormant within your heart
ぬくもりを感じるために
To feel the warmth
涙を忘れず生きてく
I live without forgetting my tears
遠い記憶にも
Even in distant memories
刻み込まれてるシステム
A system that has been carved in
微笑み取り戻すために
To regain the smile
君と共に歩いていく
I will walk with you
愛も裏切りも
Both love and betrayal
同じ数だけ潜んでる
Are hiding in equal numbers
人間を信じることに
Believing in humans
臆病にならない
I won't be afraid
まっすぐ見つめて
Staring straight ahead
明日を変えていこう
Let's change tomorrow
からくり人形の瞳のその奥
Deep within the eyes of the automaton
仕組まれた夢に
In the fabricated dream
心が揺れている
My heart is trembling
錆びついたネジを捨て去る勇気は
The courage to throw away the rusted screw...
僕の心で
In my heart
もう目覚めはじめている
it's already beginning to wake up
Dearest
作詞・作曲：浜田聖子 編曲：西田マサラ
Lyrics/Composition: Shoko Hamada, Arrangement: Masara Nishida
梅雨明け前の
Before the end of the rainy season
青空は
the blue sky
一足早く心を躍らせる
makes my heart leap a little early
今年ももうすぐ
This year, too, soon...
夏が来る
summer will come
街も人も浮かれ気分で騒めきだす
The town and its people start buzzing in a festive mood
私はと言えば
As for me...
あなたを想い
...thinking of you
この街で新しい風に吹かれて
caught in a new breeze in this town
少しの不安も抱きしめながら
While embracing even a little bit of anxiety
叶えたい明日だけを見つめて生きる
I live looking only at the tomorrow I want to fulfill
少年の心のまま大人になった人
You, who became an adult with a boy's heart
二人出会ったあの日に戻れないけど
We can't go back to the day we met
瞳を閉じれば微笑む顔が見える
If I close my eyes, I can see your smiling face
大好きなあの歌今も歌ってますか
Are you still singing that song I love?
私には聴こえる
I can hear it
優しい声とメロディ
the gentle voice and melody
弱気なときほど
Especially when I'm feeling low
あなたを思い出す
I remember you
時々自分が嫌いになるのは
The times I occasionally end up hating myself...
軽はずみな言葉で誰かを傷つけ
...are when I hurt someone with thoughtless words
その癖弱くてちっぽけだから
And yet, because I'm weak and small
逃げようとする私を叱ってください
Please scold me for trying to run away
二人で歌ったメロディ口ずさんでみれば
If I try humming the melody we sang together
涙が一筋流れて会いたくなった
A single tear falls and I miss you
受話器越しに聴いた
I heard it through the receiver
弾いて聴かせてくれた
You played it for me
リフレインするリズム
The refrain of the rhythm
胸に切なく響く
echoes painfully in my chest
巡り逢えた奇跡...
The miracle of us meeting...
鮮やかすぎるメモリ
Memories that are too vivid
迷い悩む未来も
Even in a lost and troubled future
あなたを忘れない
I won't forget you
少年の心のまま
With a boy's heart
大人になった人
The person who became an adult
二人で出会ったあの日に
To that day when the two of us met
戻れないけど
I can't go back, but...
瞳を閉じれば
If I close my eyes
微笑む顔が見える
I can see your smiling face
大好きなあの歌
That song I love so much
今も歌ってますか？
Are you still singing it now?
私には聞こえる
I can hear it
優しい声とメロディ
That gentle voice and melody
弱気な時ほど
Especially when I feel weak
あなたを思い出す
I remember you
受話器越しに聞いた
Heard over the phone receiver
聞いて聞かせてくれた
You listened and let me hear
リフレインするフレーズ
The refraining phrase
胸に切なく響く
Echoes painfully in my chest
巡り会えた季節
The season we happened to meet
鮮やかすぎるメモリ
Memories that are too vivid
迷い悩む未来も
Even in a lost and troubled future
あなたを忘れない
I won't forget you
みんな、ライブ楽しんでますかー？
Everyone, are you enjoying the live show?
ここまで、みんなは何曲知ってましたか？
How many of the songs so far did you know?
初めて聴いた曲もあったかな？
Maybe there were some you heard for the first time?
今回、尺の都合で歌えない曲もたくさんあって、
There were so many songs I couldn't sing this time due to time constraints,
平成初期のアニソンは名曲もいっぱいで、何を歌おうかすごく悩みました！
And since there are so many masterpieces among early Heisei era anime songs, I really struggled to decide what to sing!
まだまだ、盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's keep the excitement going!
今回選んだ曲とか、コラボ相手については、
As for the songs I chose this time and my collab partners,
また振り返りとかで、ゆっくりお話しさせてください。
I'll talk more about that slowly during a review stream later.
ハッシュタグも活用してくれるかな？
I hope you'll make use of the hashtag too!
えー、そして、すでに気づいている人も、もしかしたらいるかもしれないですが、
Uh, and, there might be some people who've noticed already,
実は、ここまでの曲、なんとすべてオープニング曲だったんですよ！
But actually, all the songs so far have been opening themes!
ってことは、次からは…
Which means, starting from the next one...
エンディング曲パートにいっちゃうぞー！
We're moving on to the ending theme part!
キマった。えっ、何何何？雪？
Nailed it. Eh, what, what, what? Snow?
靴の底がすり減ってる
The soles of my shoes are worn out
まるで今のココロみたい
Just like my heart is right now
他人と深く解り合うって
Truly understanding others deeply
難しいと感じたよ
I've felt that it's difficult
うなずくことしかできない自分
My self who can do nothing but nod
嫌いになってる
I'm starting to hate it
世の中には思い通りいかないことも
In this world, there are things that don't go as planned,
あるけれど
although there are...
落ち込むだけ落ち込んだら
Once you've felt as down as you can get,
笑ってまた歩かなきゃ
you have to smile and start walking again
だけど譲れない大切なもの
But the precious things I can't give up
守り通したい
I want to protect them until the end
夢実現するため
To make my dreams come true,
の犠牲はもうやだよ
I'm done with sacrifices
気持ちに嘘つくようなことはやめて
Stop doing things like lying to your feelings
YES・NO イイコは卒業しよう
Let's graduate from being the "Yes/No good kid"
そうすればきっと自分のことを
If you do that, surely
好きになれるはずだよ
you'll be able to like yourself
強気でいこう
Let's go with confidence!
一目惚れで
Falling in love at first sight,
恋に落ちた
I fell for you.
彼とは2年
It's been two years with him,
たったけど
but...
ドアを閉めた
By the sound of the door closing,
音でわかる
I can tell.
もうだめだね
It's over for us,
私たち
isn't it?
誰かと私の
Going back and forth
間を行ったり来たりしてると
between me and someone else...
えぐいていたけど
It was gut-wrenching,
ひとりになるの怖かった
but I was afraid of being alone.
魂を売るようなことはやめて
Stop doing things that sell your soul.
都合のイイコは卒業しよう
Let's graduate from being a "convenient girl."
迷いのある人生だっていいよ
It's okay to have a life full of hesitation.
どんな闇だて
No matter how deep the darkness,
超えてみせる
I will overcome it!
嫌われたくない想いが
The desire to not be hated
自由の羽根踏みつけた
trampled on the wings of freedom.
飛べないまま終わりたくない
I don't want to end without being able to fly.
思いのまま生きていたい
I want to live exactly as I feel.
気持ちに嘘つくようなことはやめて
Stop lying to your feelings.
YESなイイコは卒業しよう
Let's graduate from being a "yes girl."
そうすればきっと自分のことを
If you do that, I'm sure you can
好きになれるはずだよ
come to love yourself.
強気で行こう
Let's go forward with confidence.
迷いのある人生だっていいよ
It's okay to have a life full of hesitation.
どんな闇だて
No matter how deep the darkness,
超えてみせる
I will overcome it!
たったひとつしかない
There is only one you,
自分好きになろう
so let's come to love yourself.
Agape
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are.
君がくれるアガペー
The agape you give me,
力の限り
with all my might...
ラーイ
Light!
見つめる
Gazing at each other,
触れ合う
touching each other,
その時
in that moment...
愛は二人を試している
Love is putting the two of us to the test.
Time is now
この世の果てまで
Even unto the ends of this world...
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are.
君がくれるアガペー
The agape you give me,
力の限り
with all my might...
ラーイ
Light!
信じる
Believing,
答える
answering,
その時
in that moment...
愛が僕らを一つにする
Love makes us one.
Time is now
どこまでも生きて
Living on forever...
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are.
君がくれるアガペー
The agape you give me,
力の限り
with all my might...
ラーイ
Light!
Would you come if you in my life
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are
君がくれるアガペー
The agape that you give me
力の限り
With all my might
Would you come if you in my life
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are
君がくれるアガペー
The agape that you give me
力の限り
With all my might
Would you come if you in my life
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear you no matter where you are
君がくれるアガペー
The agape that you give me
力の限り
With all my might
Ah——
勇気の鐘 〜晴れてハレルヤII〜
The Bell of Courage ~Sunny Hallelujah II~
作詞：西東レモン / 奥井亜紀 作曲：奥井亜紀
Lyrics: Lemon Saito / Aki Okui Composition: Aki Okui
おめでとう
Congratulations
笑顔がゆれて
With swaying smiles
ゆるやかに
Gently
流れる奏鳴曲(ソナタ)
The sonata flows
ふたりとも ずいぶん
The two of you
大人に見えるよ
look quite like adults
長いこと 友達同士
We've been friends for a long time
何回も ケンカしてたね
We fought so many times, didn't we?
気がつけば ふたり
Before we knew it,
想い出が重なる
our memories overlapped
男とか 女とかじゃなく
Not as a man or a woman,
何でも話せるふたりだったね
we were two people who could talk about anything
短いようで長い道を
On this road that seems short yet long,
旅してふたりここに立ってる
we've traveled and now stand here together
高らかに鳴り響く鐘の音は
The sound of the bell ringing loudly
晴れやかな今日がゴールじゃなくて
means today's clear sky isn't the goal
お互いの胸の奥 響きあう
It resonates deep within our hearts
これからも続く長い旅をつげる
Heralding the long journey that continues
勇気の鐘
The bell of courage
夢をみる ふたりいっしょに
We dream together
ひとりでは たどりつけない
Somewhere we couldn't reach alone
邪魔なのは
What gets in the way
後悔とうすいプライド
is regret and shallow pride
彼の目に
In his eyes,
汗がにじんで
sweat wells up
うつむいて弱音吐くなら
and if he hangs his head in weakness
その頬を 泣いてでも
Even if you're crying,
たたいてあげて
give those cheeks a slap
瞬間だけの なぐさめなんて
Comfort that's only for a moment
中途半端な優しさに似てる
is like half-hearted kindness
はるか彼方に昇る太陽
The sun rising in the far distance—
顔をあげてなきゃ瞳がくもる
your eyes will cloud if you don't look up
いつまでも 鐘の音が
So the sound of the bell
響くように 深呼吸で...
echoes forever, with a deep breath...
勇気の鐘～晴れてハレルヤII～
The Bell of Courage ~Harete Hallelujah II~
深呼吸で心に風送ろう
Send a breeze to my heart with a deep breath.
だけどもしふたりめげたりしたら
But if the two of us ever get discouraged,
一番乗りで待っていてあげたい
I want to be the first one there waiting for you.
勇気の丘
The Hill of Courage.
なだらかなレンガの階段を
Up the gentle brick staircase,
腕を組みふたり登りはじめる
Hand in hand, the two of us begin to climb.
お互いに夢をかかえあえたら
If we can share our dreams with each other,
夢に近づくたびクレッシェンドする
They crescendo every time we get closer.
勇気の鐘
The Bell of Courage.
Alone
乾いた風が吹く
A dry wind blows.
街は凍えている
The town is freezing.
いくつもの季節がそっと音もなく
Many seasons have passed quietly,
過ぎ去ったのだろう
without a sound.
行き交う人はみな
Everyone passing by
重い荷物背負って
is carrying a heavy burden.
遠くに揺れる陽炎の中に
In the heat haze shimmering in the distance,
明日を見つける
they search for tomorrow.
この手からこぼれ落ちる
Slipping through my fingers,
砂のような感情
feelings like sand.
あの時胸に刺さった
The words that pierced my heart back then
言葉が不意にうずくけど
suddenly ache again, but...
果てしない夜を数えながら
While counting the endless nights,
自分のカケラ探していた
I was searching for pieces of myself.
失うほどにこの思いは
The more I lose, the stronger
確かになっていく
this feeling becomes.
今ならきっと歩いていける
Now I'm sure I can keep walking,
どこまでも
no matter how far.
どうしてこの空は
Why is this sky
こんなに広いのだろう
so incredibly vast?
叫んでみても声にならなくて
Even if I scream, no sound comes out,
涙があふれた
and my tears overflow.
自由に風切って
Cutting through the wind with freedom,
鳥たちはどこへ行くの
where are the birds heading?
少しだけ時間の海に
For just a moment, in the sea of time,
同じ場所に戻れない
I can't go back to the same place.
このまま夢を諦めても
Even if I were to give up on my dream like this,
高鳴る鼓動抑えきれない
I can't suppress my racing heartbeat.
いつかはきっと近づきたい
I want to get closer someday
あの雲の高さ
to the height of those clouds.
もう一度ここから
Once more, from here.
空に翼広げ
Spreading wings in the sky,
旅立つよ
I'm setting off on a journey.
どんな路も辿り着けるはず
I should be able to reach any path.
果てない夜を数えながら
While counting the endless nights,
自分の欠片探していた
I was searching for pieces of myself.
失うほどにこの想いが
The more I lose, the more these feelings
確かになってゆく
become certain.
今ならきっと歩いてゆける
Now I'm sure I can keep walking,
どこまでも
no matter how far.
はい、今日はみんな来てくれてありがとうございました。
All right, thank you all for coming today.
今日のライブはみんな、どうだったかな？
How did you all like today's live?
悲しいことにお別れの時間が来てしまいました。
Sadly, it's time for us to say goodbye.
最後はみんなに懐かしい気持ちを噛み締めてもらいたいので、
I want everyone to savor a nostalgic feeling at the end,
最後の曲を歌う前にお知らせさせてください。
so please let me make some announcements before the final song.
まずはこちら、お待たせしました。先日シングルを公開した
First, here it is—thanks for waiting. The MV for "Atelier,"
アトリエ
Atelier
「アトリエ」のMVが公開されます！
the single released the other day, is being released!
アトリエ過激派もこれで大満足だね。
Even the Atelier radicals will be very satisfied with this.
思わず考察したくなるようなMVになってるから、たくさん見てね。
It's an MV that'll make you want to theorize, so please watch it a lot.
次に、今年も有ります。
Next, we have it again this year.
活動4周年記念 9月22日 販売開始
4th Anniversary Memorial - Sales Start Sep 22nd
不知火フレア活動4周年記念グッズ！
Shiranui Flare 4th Anniversary Memorial Goods!
なんと、ついに出します。不知火フレア 1stアルバム「Canvas」。
And finally, I'm releasing it: Shiranui Flare's 1st album, "Canvas".
不知火フレア 1st アルバム「Canvas」
Shiranui Flare 1st Album "Canvas"
アルバム名は「Canvas」。ジャケットはコタテユウ先生に
The album is titled "Canvas." The cover art was
描き下ろしていただきました！
specially drawn by Kotate Yuu-sensei!
楽曲は初めてのオリ曲「Smile & Go!!」を始め、
As for the tracks, starting with my first original song, "Smile & Go!!",
今年までに歌った曲を加えて、なんとあの「Skyreach」を
I've added songs I've sung up until this year, and even "Skyreach"...
奥井さん本人とデュエットした特別ボーナストラックを収録！
...a special bonus track duet with Okui-san herself is included!
ソロとはまた違ったSkyreachを聞いてみませんか？
Won't you give this version of Skyreach a listen?
続いて、染宮うるは先生描き下ろし、
Next, specially drawn by Somemiya Uruha-sensei,
ランダムラバーストラップ
Random Rubber Straps
ランダムラバーストラップ。
Random Rubber Straps.
今までの衣装に新衣装、アトリエの衣装の、とってもキュートなラバーストラップになってます。
They're very cute rubber straps featuring my past outfits, new outfit, and Atelier outfit.
どの衣装の私もしようも可愛いでしょう？
I'm cute in every single one of these outfits, right?
え、さらに、今回のアルバム「Canvas」をイメージしたリュックサック。
And there's more! A backpack inspired by the album "Canvas".
「Canvas」リュックサック
"Canvas" Backpack
フロント部分のファスナーには、はばたくエルフレチャームがついてます。
The front zipper features a flapping El-friend charm.
開け閉めすると飛んでるように見えて可愛いね。
It's cute how it looks like it's flying when you open and close it.
裏生地は私や君たちをモチーフにした柄なんかも入ってるよ。
The lining also has patterns inspired by me and all of you.
私とお揃いのカバンでお出かけしない？
Won't you go out with a bag that matches mine?
えっ、さらにさらに、こちらも今回のアルバムイラストで
And wait, there's even more! Based on the album illustration,
「Canvas」手帳型マルチスマホケース
"Canvas" Notebook-style Multi-Smartphone Case
私が持ってる本の表紙と同じデザインの、
a notebook-style multi-smartphone case
手帳型マルチスマホケース。
with the same design as the book I'm holding.
デザインは金の箔押し付きで、本当に本みたいですっごくオシャレだよ。
The design has gold foil stamping, it's really like a book and very stylish.
活動4周年記念フルセット
4th Anniversary Memorial Full Set
そして気になる全部セットは、数量限定だけど書き下ろし直筆メッセージ！
And the full set includes a hand-written message—limited quantity!
愛情込めて一枚一枚書いて君に届けるからね。
I'll write each one with love and send them to you.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
通常版は複製にはなっちゃうんだけど、数量限定とは違うメッセージ、
The standard version will be a reproduction, but it'll have a different message,
少し長めに書いちゃおうかな。
maybe I'll write a bit more than the limited version.
最後にお知らせです。この後、メンバー限定ミニライブ！
Final announcement: After this, a members-only mini-live!
メンバー限定ミニライブ
Members-Only Mini-Live
今回コンセプトの都合上、オリジナルソング歌わなかったので、
Due to the concept, I didn't sing any original songs today,
ほんの少しだけオリ曲を歌って踊っちゃおうかなって思います。
so I'm thinking of singing and dancing a few original songs there.
よかったら遊びに来てください！
Please come and hang out if you'd like!
はいということで、お知らせは以上です。
All right, that's all for the announcements.
改めて、4周年とみんな来てくれて、今日は本当にありがとうございました。
Once again, thank you so much for coming today and celebrating my 4th anniversary.
5年目もよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to your support in my 5th year too.
はあ、もう終わりか。
Phew, is it over already?
夏ももう終わっちゃうな。
Summer is coming to an end too.
みんなと出会えて、ほんとに、ほんとによかった。
I'm truly, truly glad that I was able to meet everyone.
ここが、私の幸せの場所です。
This is my place of happiness.
夏影 作詞・作曲 麻枝准 (Key)
Natsukage - Lyrics/Composition: Jun Maeda (Key)
二人分の...
Two people's...
夏影
Summer Shadows
青空
Blue sky
君は手で囲った
You framed it with your hands
陽の匂いの
The scent of the sun
する楠
on the camphor tree
僕は手に結んだ
I tied it in my hands
風を背に
With the wind at our backs,
今 僕らが
now we
走り抜けたよ
ran through
あの青空 目指してた
aiming for that blue sky
超えてゆく はるかな夏も
Passing by, even the distant summers
渡る川の流れも
and the flow of the river we cross,
いつか変わって
will change someday
いつか忘れて
Someday we'll forget
同じ想い 守れずにいる
unable to protect the same feelings
二人 青空に
The two of us, into the blue sky
ひこうき雲 飛ばした
sent up contrails
奏でてる
Playing out,
子供たちの手には
in the hands of the children
虫籠
is an insect cage,
あの思い出
those memories
超えてゆく はるかな夢も
Passing by, even the distant dreams
流れる川のほとりを いつも一人で
Along the banks of the flowing river, always alone
いつも歩いた 今は違う道を
I always walked, now on a different path
遠くなる はるかな夏よ
Receding into the distance, oh distant summer
流れる街で
In the flowing town,
僕ら遊んだ
we played,
僕ら生きてた
we lived
今も思えてる
I can still remember
夏影
Summer Lights